Alejandro Munoz

Software Engineer

almunz93@gmail.com • 954-213-7276 • al-mun.eithub.io/portfolio/

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience Software Engineer specialized in Frontend/Backend development, Domain Driven

Design, Test-Driven Design, and Event-Driven Architecture. Experienced in

overhauling mobile apps and patient UIs in the healthcare industry.

Languages JavaScript/TypeScript, React/Native, Java, Spring Boot, Python, HTML, CSS

Tools Atlassian Jira, Agile Kanban, Git Version Control, GitHub, Kendo React, Jest

Testing Library, Postman, Swagger, Kafka, MongoDB noSQL, CI/CD.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ChenMed Miami Gardens, FL

Software Engineer

12/2022 - 12/2023

Technologies: React TypeScript/JavaScript, Kendo, Java 21, Spring Boot, MongoDB, Kafka, Swagger, Docker.

- Collaborated on a 9 person team in the overhaul of a legacy dashboard resulting in increased usage by doctors and staff.
- Prepared and deployed various microservices and UIs to production environments using Event Driven Architecture, Test Driven Design, and Domain Driven Design principles.
- Successfully deployed new monorepo architecture, as part of Frontend platform team, streamlining development processes.
- Implemented Unit, Integration, and Component tests for both Frontend and Backend projects.
- Collaborated on a 14 person team in the successful transition of GoNative app to React Native.
- Worked closely with Product Managers, UX Designers, and QA engineers to deliver scalable, reliable software solutions.
- Wrote tickets, documented changes, and reviewed Pull Requests.

Software Engineer Intern

08/2022 - 12/2022

Technologies: React Native Typescript, GoNative, Java, Spring Boot, Material UI, Space

- Handled Frontend maintenance of Intune HealthTM and TeamCareTM apps as part of a 3 person team.
- Worked closely with Product and UX to prepare the overhaul of Go Native apps.
- Responsible for fixing bugs and implementing new features for Go Native apps.
- Successfully onboarded and trained 2 new interns during internship.

Burdette Beckmann Inc

Hollywood, FL

Accounts Receivable Associate

07/2019 - 08/2022

- Analyzed financial data for 100% accuracy relative to invoices.
- Addressed and resolved data discrepancies.
- Organized and managed financial data for over 20 accounts.
- Communicated with multiple manufacturers to obtain financial statements.

EDUCATION

Broward College

10/2017 - 09/2020

- Bachelor of Applied Science
 - Web Development, Computer Science
- Associate's in Arts